Hyukkyu Kang

• Pohang, Republic of Korea ☑ hkkang@dblab.postech.ac.kr • hyukkyukang.github.io in Hyukkyu Kang • Hyukkyu Kang

Summary

I am a Ph.D. Student in the Data Systems Lab Z at Pohang University of Science and Technology (POSTECH) 🗹. I am doing research under the supervision of Professor Wook-Shin Han 🗹. My research interests are in the area of Natural Language Processing (NLP) and Information Retrieval (IR). I got my B.S. degree in Computer Science and Engineering from POSTECH.

Education

Pohang University of Science and Technology Ph.D. in Computer Science and Engineering (M.S./Ph.D. integration)	Sep. 2019 – Present
Pohang University of Science and Technology B.S. in Computer Science and Engineering	Feb. 2015 – Aug. 2019
Work Experience	

Research Intern Dec. 2018 – Aug. 2019

Database Lab, POSTECH

• Researched Natural Language Interface to Databases (NLIDB)

Research Intern June 2018 – Aug. 2018

Center of Netmarble AI Revolution, Netmarble Company

o Developed AI player for a real-time strategy game using reinforcement learning

Projects

Development of a Conversational, Self-tuning DBMS

Sep. 2019 - Feb. 2023

 My goal was to develop a deep learning-based text-to-SQL semantic parsing model that can provide a natural language interface to database systems

Activities

Global Leadership Program (GLP)

Feb. 2017 - Dec. 2017

Computer Vision Lab, POSTECH

• Researched real-time object detection & tracking

Postech Laboratory for Unix Security (PLUS)

June 2015 - Dec. 2017

Studied linux system vulnerability and participated in various CTFs (e.g., DEFCON CTF 2017)

Teaching Assistant

CSED 273 Digital System Design, POSTECH	Spring 2020
CSED 312 Operating System, POSTECH	Fall 2019

Technologies

Programming Languages: C/C++, Python, Scala, Java, JavaScript

Libraries & Software: PyTorch, TensorFlow, Databases, React

Communication language: Korean, English, Chinese